# **PANTELIS MANIOTIS**

Address: 66 Parklands Drive, Chelmsford, Essex, UK | Post Code: CM1 7SP | Mobile phone: +44 7716651128

## PROFILE:

A competent data scientist with a comprehensive knowledge and experience in analysing large datasets and developing forecasting models. His fields of knowledge include:

Machine Learning

Database design

• Statistical Analysis

• Deep Learning

Data cleaning

• Combinatorial optimization

Data Analysis

• Automation of processes

Software Engineering

Please check my online portfolio for a complete list of various projects, publications, tools I have used, etc.

## WORK EXPERIENCE:

#### UNIVERSITY OF ESSEX

Wivenhoe Park, Colchester, UK

Email: pantmaniotis@gmail.com

Oct 2016 – Sept 2020

Data Science / Research and Development

- Simulated 5G mobile networks for the delivery of VR applications, in order to maximise the Quality of Experience users enjoy and minimise the operating cost.
- Extracted valuable insights from the statistical analysis and visualisation of large datasets regarding the users' consumption patterns.
- Developed Machine Learning and Deep Learning models, in order to optimise the performance of the mobile networks.

#### NDC TECHNOLOGIES

Heybridge, Maldon, United Kingdom May 2018 – September 2018

Data Analyst

- Developed a standalone MS Access Database in Access 2016 for data collection and data analysis processes.
- Built front-end screen with user menus, input forms, reports forms, using custom procedures in VBA code and macros to increase consistency of data.
- Performed data cleaning techniques to ensure data correctness and accuracy.

HELLENIC ARMY

Evros, Greece

Data Analyst March 2015 – December 2015

• Managed a large volume of sensitive military data using MS Office.

- Maintained and improved the tools and applications used in MS Excel, MS Access, using VBA.
- Optimized data collection procedures and generated reports on a weekly and monthly basis.

#### EDUCATION:

## UNIVERSITY OF ESSEX

Wivenhoe Park, Colchester, Essex, UK

• PhD in Computer Science and Electronic Engineering

October 2016 – September 2020

#### ARISTOTLE UNIVERSITY of THESSALONIKI (AUTh)

• BSc and MSc in Electrical and Computer Engineering (5 year degree) (7.02/10)

Thessaloniki, Greece September 2007– April 2015

#### SKILLS:

- Specialized computer software knowledge (MS Office, MATLAB, Tableu, SPSS, LaTeX, Adobe Photoshop, GIMP)
- Programming skills (Python, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Keras, SQL, R, C, C++, VBA, Bash Shell).
- Excellent knowledge of Linux, Windows, Mac OS operating systems.
- Excellent knowledge of English and Greek.

#### INTERESTS:

- Keeping up to date with the state-of-the-art technology advancements.
- Testing computer software capabilities.
- Playing chess.
- Exercising.